urbancompass.com 2016-04-02

# Privacy Policy - Compass

This Privacy Policy describes the policies and procedures of Urban Compass, Inc. ("we", "our" or "us") on the collection, use and disclosure of your information on www.compass.com (the "Site") and the services, features, content or applications we offer (collectively with the Site, the "Services"). When you use the Services, you are consenting to the collection, transfer, manipulation, storage, disclosure and other uses of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

##### What Does This Privacy Policy Cover?

This Privacy Policy covers the treatment of personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") gathered when you use or access the Services. This Privacy Policy also covers our treatment of any Personal Information which landlords, tenants or our business partners share with us, or that we share with our business partners.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that we do not own or control, including but not limited to any landlords, renters, third party websites, services and applications (“Third Party Services”) that you elect to access through the Services or to individuals that we do not manage or employ. While we attempt to facilitate access only to those Third Party Services that share our respect for your privacy or that you request through your use of the Services, we cannot take responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those Third Party Services. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any Third Party Services you access.

##### What About International Users?

YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE MAINTAINED ON AND TRANSFERRED TO COMPUTERS LOCATED OUTSIDE OF YOUR STATE, PROVINCE, COUNTRY OR OTHER GOVERNMENTAL JURISDICTION WHERE THE PRIVACY LAWS MAY NOT BE AS PROTECTIVE AS THOSE IN YOUR JURISDICTION. IF YOU ARE LOCATED OUTSIDE THE UNITED STATES AND CHOOSE TO PROVIDE INFORMATION TO US, WE TRANSFER PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THE UNITED STATES AND PROCESSES IT THERE. YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES AND YOUR SUBMISSION OF SUCH INFORMATION EACH REPRESENTS YOUR AGREEMENT TO THAT TRANSFER.

##### What Information Do We Collect?

YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE MAINTAINED ON AND TRANSFERRED TO COMPUTERS LOCATED OUTSIDE OF YOUR STATE, PROVINCE, COUNTRY OR OTHER GOVERNMENTAL JURISDICTION WHERE THE PRIVACY LAWS MAY NOT BE AS PROTECTIVE AS THOSE IN YOUR JURISDICTION. IF YOU ARE LOCATED OUTSIDE THE UNITED STATES AND CHOOSE TO PROVIDE INFORMATION TO US, WE TRANSFER PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THE UNITED STATES AND PROCESSES IT THERE. YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES AND YOUR SUBMISSION OF SUCH INFORMATION EACH REPRESENTS YOUR AGREEMENT TO THAT TRANSFER.

The information we gather enables us to personalize, improve and continue to operate the Services. In connection with certain aspects of the Services, we may request and collect some of your Personal Information. We collect the following types of information from our users.

**Information You Provide Us:** You may choose to provide us with certain information that could include, without limitation, Personal Information, such as your name, email address, employment information, social security number, demographic information, rental listing information, credit card or other payment information, background check information, rental application information, information contained in any lease you are negotiating or entering into, photo identification, reference letters, bank statements, income tax returns, or address of a listing you intend to rent, or other information we request from you that is required by law. You acknowledge that this information may be personal to you, and by providing this information to us, we may store such information and contact you to send you information about the Services. Information Collected Automatically: We also receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with the Services. We automatically receive and record information in our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, search queries, cookie information, and the listings and pages you request. We also record the details of your activity on the Services.

**Information Collected Using Cookies:** Cookies are pieces of text that may be provided to your computer through your web browser when you access a website. Your browser stores cookies in a manner associated with each website you visit. We use cookies to enable our servers to recognize your web browser and tell us how and when you visit the Site and otherwise use the Services through the Internet. Our cookies do not, by themselves, contain Personal Information, and we do not combine the general information collected through cookies with other Personal Information to tell us who you are. As noted, however, we do use cookies to identify that your web browser has accessed aspects of the Services. Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. This Privacy Policy covers our use of cookies only and does not cover the use of cookies by third parties, including our partners. We do not control when or how third parties place cookies on your computer. For example, third party websites to which a link points may set cookies on your computer. Ads appearing on the Services may be delivered to users by our advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Compass and does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties, including advertisers or partners.

**Aggregate Information:** We collect statistical information about how both users, collectively, use the Services ("Aggregate Information"). Some of this information is derived from Personal Information. This statistical information is not Personal Information and cannot be tied back to you or your web browser. This type of aggregate data enables us to figure out how often users use parts of the Services so that we can make the Services appealing to as many users as possible, and improve the Services. As part of this use of information, we may provide aggregate information to our partners about how our users, collectively, use our site. We share this type of statistical data so that our partners also understand how often people use their services and the Services, so that they, too, may provide you with an optimal online experience. Again, we never disclose aggregate information to a partner in a manner that would identify you personally.

We use conversion tracking from third-party advertising platforms, including Google and Facebook. These advertising programs use cookies to help determine aggregate, anonymous actions people took on our website after clicking an ad. 

##### Is Personal Information About Me Secure?

You need to prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. We endeavor to protect account information to ensure that it is kept private; however, we cannot guarantee the security of any account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time. We otherwise store all of our information, including your IP address information, using industry-standard security techniques. We do not guarantee or warrant that such techniques will prevent unauthorized access to information about you we store, Personal Information or otherwise.

##### How, And With Whom, Is My Information Shared?

**Third Party Services:** At times, you may be able to access other Third Party Services through the Services, for example by clicking on links to those Third Party Services from within the Site. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of these Third Party Services, and you are responsible for reading and understanding those Third Party Services' privacy policies. This Privacy Policy only governs information collected on the Services.

**Email Communications with Us and Other Users:** As part of the Services, you may occasionally receive email and other communications from us, such as communications relating to promotions we are offering through the Services. You acknowledge and agree that by posting information on or through the Services, or requesting that we do so on your behalf, we and our agents, the landlords or tenants relevant to your request for Services, and others may send you e-mail, contact you or engage in other communications that they determine in their sole discretion relate to your profile or use of the Services. You may opt-out of receiving such communications by following the instructions included with such emails, or emailing us at [opt-out@compass.com](mailto:opt-out@compass.com), but then you may not have access to certain features of the Services. In addition, we and others you interact with through the Services may wish to send you a house-warming gift or other expression of appreciation, and you acknowledge and agree that we may share your Personal Information with such persons, or use your Personal Information for such purposes.

**Information Shared with Our Agents:** We employ and contract with people and other entities that perform certain tasks on our behalf and who are under our control (our "Agents"). We may need to share Personal Information with our Agents in order to provide Services to you. Unless we tell you differently, our Agents do not have any right to use Personal Information or other information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. You hereby consent to our sharing of Personal Information with our Agents.

**Information Disclosed Pursuant to Business Transfers:** In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the transferred business assets. Moreover, if we, or substantially all of our assets, were acquired, or if we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of us or our assets may continue to use your Personal Information as set forth in this policy.

**Information Disclosed for Our Protection and the Protection of Others:** We also reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information as we reasonably believe is necessary to (i) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, (ii) enforce the Terms of Service or this Privacy Policy, including investigation of potential violations thereof or hereof, (iii) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, (iv) respond to user support requests, or (v) protect our rights, property or safety, our users and the public. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and spam/malware prevention.

**Information We Share in Connection with the Services Performed for You:** The information you provide, including, without limitation, your profile information, search criteria, user name, email, address, and co-habitant information, may be used to facilitate and provide the services for you and transactions within the Services. This may include, without limitation, sharing your Personal Information with potential landlords, agents, brokers, co-brokers, as applicable to your request for Services; and if you are landlord, we may also share your Personal Information (such as name, listing address, etc.) to potential tenants in connection with the Services.

**Information We Share with Your Consent:** Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Information may be shared with third parties, and will be able to prevent the sharing of this information.

##### What Information Can I Access?

We may allow you to access certain information about you for the purpose of viewing, and in certain situations, updating that information. This list will change as the Services change. When you update information, however, we often maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. You may request deletion of your account by sending an e-mail to our webmaster at [opt-out@compass.com](mailto:opt-out@compass.com). Please note that some information may remain in our records after deletion of your account.

##### What Happens When There Are Changes To This Privacy Policy?

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes in the way we collect or use information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Services or sending you an email. A user is bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when he or she uses the Services after such changes have been first posted.

##### What If I Have Questions Or Concerns?

If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy using the Services, please send us a detailed message to [notices@compass.com](mailto:notices@compass.com). We will make every effort to resolve your concerns.

Effective Date: April 10th, 2013
